makinghomeaffordable.gov 2015-06-03

# Privacy Policy

​PRIVACY POLICY AND LEGAL NOTICES FOR TREASURY DEPARTMENT PUBLICLY-ACCESSIBLE WEB SITES

**Privacy Policy**

The MakingHomeAffordable.gov web site is administered by the Department of the Treasury. If you visit the MakingHomeAffordable.gov web site to read or download information, we collect and store only the following information about you: the name of the domain from which you access the Internet; the date and time you access our site; and the Internet address of the web site from which you linked directly to our site. We do not collect or use any information subject to the Privacy Act, such as name and address. Raw data logs are used for no other purposes and are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration Guidance.

We will not obtain personally identifying information about you when you visit our site unless you voluntarily choose to provide such information to us by E-mail, by completing a comment form, forum registration site, or other on-line form. The Department of the Treasury does not give, sell or transfer personal information to third parties unless required by law, such as the Freedom of Information Act.

We use **Google Analytics**   to generate aggregate summary data about visits to Treasury web sites to assess what information is of most  interest, identify system performance or problem areas, and to participate in the [National Digital Strategy](http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/omb/egov/digital-government/digital-government.html#measure-performance).   **Please  visit ****Google Privacy Policy and How to Opt Out of Google Cookies.**

Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits.

For information specific to any Treasury bureau web site regarding the use of cookies and other privacy information, please review the privacy policy at that bureau's web site.

We strongly discourage you from sending any personal information, such as a social security number, address or any other personal identifiable information. It may be necessary on certain bureau web sites to collect personally identifiable information (name, E-mail address, social security number, or other unique identifier), but only if specifically and knowingly provided by you. Personally identifying information you provide will be used only for such other purposes as are described at the point of collection by the bureau asking for the information. Visit the Privacy Policy pages of bureau web sites for information on controls in place to ensure the security and confidentiality of any personally identifiable information collected by bureaus.

For more information on the Privacy Act visit our [Privacy Act page](http://www.treasury.gov/FOIA/Pages/privacy_index.aspx). A discussion of rights under the Privacy Act is available at [Publications.usa.gov](http://www.publications.usa.gov/).

**Notice of Monitoring**

You are entering an Official United States Government System which may be used only for authorized purposes. The Government may monitor and audit usage of this system, and all persons are hereby notified that use of this system constitutes consent to such monitoring and auditing.

Unauthorized attempts to upload information and/or change information on these web sites are strictly prohibited and are subject to prosecution under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and 18 U.S.C. §§1001 and 1030.

**Disclaimer of Endorsement**

The Department of the Treasury does not endorse any commercial product, service, process, or enterprise. Links to other web sites and references to any commercial product or enterprise are provided solely for the convenience of the user and do not constitute an endorsement or recommendation. The Department of the Treasury assumes no responsibility for the content or operation of other web sites.

**Disclaimer of Liability**

The United States Government (including the Department of the Treasury) makes no warranty, express or implied, including the warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and assumes no legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy, completeness, or usefulness of any information, apparatus, product, or process described or depicted on this web site and does not represent that its use would not infringe privately owned rights.

**External Links and Social Media/3rd Party Sites**

This web site includes links to federal and non-federal external sites. Non-federal websites do not necessarily operate under the same laws, regulations, and policies as federal websites. If you click a link to an outside website, such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Flickr, or other external site, you will leave the MakingHomeAffordable.gov site and are subject to the privacy and security policies of the owners/sponsors of the outside website.

> a. **Treasury's Purpose in  Using Social Media - **The Department of the Treasury uses 3rd party social media sites such as Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube as additional means of reaching the public and directing people to www.MakingHomeAffordable.gov, which is the official web site of the Making Home Affordable Program.
> 
> b. **Treasury** **  does not use, maintain, or share Personally Identifiable Information (PII) made available through social media/3rd party sites.** You can access information published to these sites from the top navigation icons or MakingHomeAffordable.gov Social Hub page without having an account with or subscribing to these 3rd party services. If you access one of these sites without an account, no Personally Identifiable Information is exposed to Treasury.  If you subscribe to one of these services and your account name, on-line profile, or comments you make happens to reveal personally identifiable information, we will not use, maintain, or share that information outside the agency.
> 
> c. **  Please Review the  Privacy Policies of these Social Media/3rd Party Sites.** You should familiarize yourself with the privacy policies of any social media site or 3rd party site you use. Some of these sites may use persistent cookies in order to improve the service they provide to their users.[ Instructions to opt out of receiving cookies are available at USA.gov](http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml), the official portal of the U.S. Government.  If you actually subscribe to these services, you may be revealing personally identifiable information to a 3rd party, non-government entity. Since our social media content is available to the general public, if you make a comment on a social media site, any information in your comment, as well as your profile name and any other public profile information, will be available to the general public to see. 
> 
> Privacy Policies: [Facebook](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php), [Twitter](http://twitter.com/privacy), [YouTube](http://www.youtube.com/t/privacy_at_youtube),  [Flickr](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/flickr/details.html), and Google.
> 
> d. **Mitigating Other Privacy Risks** \- Only authorized Treasury employees tasked with administering Treasury social media accounts will have access to those accounts.

**Copyright Status**

No copyright may be claimed for any work on this web site that was created or maintained by Federal employee in the course of their duties. Images and text appearing on this web site may be freely copied. Credit is requested. If copyrighted material appears on the site, or is reached through a link on this site, the copyright holder must be consulted before the material may be reproduced.

**Official Seal, Names and Symbols**

Federal law prohibits use of any symbol, emblem, seal, insignia or badge of any entity of the Department of Treasury or any colorable imitation of such words, initials, symbols, emblems, or seals in connection with any advertisement, solicitation, business activity, or product where such use could reasonably be interpreted as conveying the false impression that such advertisement, solicitation, business activity, or product is in any manner approved, endorsed, sponsored, or authorized by, or associated with, the Department of the Treasury or any organization within the Department. See 18 U.S.C. § 701, 31 U.S.C. § 333 and 31 C.F.R. Part 37.

Please see [Site Policies and Notices ](http://www.treasury.gov/SitePolicies/Pages/site-policy.aspx)for additional notices related to the MakingHomeAffordable.gov web site.
